Ashwani Kumar V

Senior DevOps Engineer

- **** +91 7989 121 975
- ✓ avardhineni7@gmail.com
- ♥ Hyderabad, IN
- in linkedin.com/in/avk-sd
- github.com/SimplifiedDevOps

SUMMARY

9+ years of experience in IT field which includes 6+ years in handling AWS Cloud environments, Build and Administer Micro-Services architecture through K8S & AWS EKS.

Proficiency in working in DevOps lifecycle management environment, creating build & release pipelines, Infrastructure Automation & Configuration Management in multiple environments.

Analytical, committed, persistent individual and reliable team member. Continuously learning and acquiring new knowledge and skills.

KEY SKILLS

Linux System Administration Bash, Python Scripting AWS Cloud, Boto3 AWS Security, DevSecOps Terraform Ansible, Packer Git/Git Hub, Bitbucket, Code Commit Maven, JFrog, Sonarqube Nginx, Apache Tomcat Jenkins, CodeBuild Docker, CodeDeploy Kubernetes, AWS EKS Helm Charts, CodePipeline Prometheus & Grafana CloudWatch AWS Lambda, API Gateway JIRA

AWS Cloud Administration, Terraform & Ansible Automation, Kubernetes Admin with DevOps Lifecycle

Professional Experience

Senior Cloud Engineer, Visionet Systems Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru Date: July 2021 – Till date

Job Profile: Build and Release Management, Deployment Automation, and Kubernetes Administration.

Cloud Engineer, TCS, Hyderabad

Payroll: Ivytel Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru,

Date: January 2018 - July 2021

Job Profile: AWS Administration & DevOps Engineer

Module Lead, Mindtree LTD. Hyderabad,
Date: February 2015 – December 2017
Job Profile: AWS Administration & Infrastructure Automation

Employment History

Roles and Responsibilities

- 1. Responsible for **fault-tolerance**, **high-availability**, **scalability** and **security** on AWS Infrastructure and platform.
- Good understanding and implementation of Microservices Concepts and Best Practices.
- 3. Responsible for **Implementation of CI/CD Pipelines** with automated build and test systems.
- 4. Responsible for **Production Deployment** using **Multiple Deployment** Strategies.
- 5. **Automating the AWS Infrastructure** and Platform Deployment with Infrastructure as a Code.
- 6. Build and maintain tools for **deployment**, **monitoring** and operations.
- 7. Support and **troubleshoot scalability**, **high availability**, performance, **monitoring**, **backup and restoration** of different environments.
- 8. Able to carry out POCs to make sure that suggested design technologies meet the requirements.
- 9. Evaluate **new tools, technologies** and processes to improve the speed, efficiency and **scalability of CI/CD environments**.
- 10. Used **Jira as a Change Management**, Work Management, Scrum Agile tool. Updating the Application team to track the status of User Stories.

Skills and Experience

- 1. Embedding **Security** at every step of SDLC with various **DevSecOps tools**.
- Expertise in deploying at scale, various Containerized web, data and service applications using Docker, Kubernetes, Elastic Kubernetes
 Service (EKS), Elastic Container Services (ECS), CloudWatch, and other monitoring solutions.
- 3. Strong experience in **40+ AWS Services** in Compute, Storage, Database, IAM, Monitoring, Security vectors.

DevSecOps Tools

Git Hooks & Talisman Mutation Tests - PIT SonarQube

Trivy Imaga Scar

Trivy Image Scan

OPA Confest

KubeSec

DAST

OWASAP ZAP

CIS Benchmarking & Kube-Bench

Istio

Kiali

Falco

KubeScan

HashiCorp Vault

EDUCATION

<u>Education History</u>

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -Associate Hashicorp Certified - Terraform Associate

- Configured AWS Security Services such as IAM, KMS, ACM, WAF, Inspector, Trusted Advisor, Cloud Trail and Guard Duty to secure resources at multiple layers.
- 5. Used **Terraform to build** multiple environments such as Dev, Staging and Prod using AWS DevOps workflow.
- Standardized the **Terraform modules** for all the resources in AWS Cloud. This helped in **reducing the code time** and re-usability of the modules.
- 7. Automated the **creation of Golden AMI** through Packer and used **Ansible for Application Configuration.**
- 8. Extensively **used Ansible** to **install and configure** all the DevOps tools. Also **Dynamically configured the inventory file** to avoid manual input of IP address in the host file.
- 9. Used Jenkins Pipelines to drive all Micro Services builds out to the Docker/ECR registry and then deployed to Kubernetes/ECS/EKS, and managed the application with various Kubernetes Objects also integrated with Jira and Slack to send build state information.
- 10. **Optimize Jenkins container** Configurations such as mount docker runtime inside container as a volume, fixing permissions on docker.sock, and **scripted Jenkins configurations** in to a Jenkinsfile to run Single Pipeline and MultiBranch Pipeline jobs.
- 11. Experience in **administrating Kubernetes** and a good understanding of **manifest management with Helm** along with expertise in Ingress Controller and **Service mesh with Istio** for Pod Communication and Encryption.
- 12. Used **Terraform to automate** the EKS Cluster and **integrated Terraform in CI/CD Pipelines** to automate provisioning of Servers.
- 13. **Automated tasks** such as System Checks, Adding Tags, Monitoring and Remote Administration, Backup and Restore, Scheduled tasks, Clean-up, Data Visualizations, Send Notifications, CI/CD related tasks **through Python Scripting**.
- 14. **Configured ELK/EFK ElasticStack** for deep search and data analytics, fluentD for centralized logging, log enrichment and parsing and Kibana for powerful and beautiful data visualizations.
- 15. Used **Jira as Change Management** and **Scrum Agile tool**. Updating the applications team in order to track the status of the user stories and defects.
- 16. Configured Prometheus Server and its components such as Grafana, Alert Manager, ServiceMonitor, Prometheus Rules to monitor all Cluster Nodes, K8S Components, Microservices Applications and Redis Data broker.
- 17. **Successfully upgraded** the Kubernetes and Jenkins by following the best practices and effective took the **backup of ETCD** database and performed timely restore drills.
- 18. **Performed Cost Optimization** with Kubecost to avoid overspending on the resources.

Looking Forward To Learn

- 1. Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps
- 2. GCP
- 3. CKA Certification
- 4. New DevOps and DevSecOps tools that emerge during my DevOps Engineer Journey.